记得以前我们没孩子时
Remember before when we don't have kids,
周六可以整天躺在床上
we can just lie in bed on Saturday.
我们就是那么怀上他们的
That's how we got them.
我为什么非要如此性感
Why did I have to be so sexy?
几个月前 卢克加入了足球队
A few months ago, Luke joined the club soccer team.
刚开始我们高兴得很
And at first, we were thrilled.
后来我们意识到
But then we realized
那会占据我们整个周末
it takes over your whole weekend.
而且不像周末性爱马拉松那么过瘾
And not in the cool marathon way.
卢克常常坐冷板凳
Luke sits on the bench a lot,
那就意味着我们要在烈日下坐上8个小时
which means we sit in the hot sun for like eight hours
就为了看他踢5分钟球
just to see him play five minutes.
但5分钟能发生很多 说说上周的事
But what a five minutes. Tell'em about last week.
卢克用脸阻挡了一个进球
Oh, yeah. Luke stopped a goal with his face.
-他不记得实在太可惜了 -是啊
- Too bad he doesn't remember that. - Yeah.
要是我们今天不去看卢克比赛了呢
What if we sent Luke to the game without us today?
-这可不行 -为什么不行
- We can't do that. - Why not?
我们不会因为错过一次比赛
Missing one tournament doesn't
就成了糟糕的父母
make us bad parents.
我妈从没参加过我的活动
My mom never went to any of my stuff.
我不也好好的吗
I'm fine.
她为什么不参加你的活动
Why didn't she go to any of your stuff?
因为她太争强好胜了
Because she was an incredibly competitive woman
不愿意看到我在某一方面表现出色
who didn't like to see me do very well at anything,
但我认为现在谁是赢家一目了然
but I think it's pretty clear who won.
我现在还要工作
I'm working now, you know,
我非常需要利用周末时间
and I really need my weekends back
去做些杂事
to -- to catch up on errands.
我也说不清 但我感觉那样不对
I don't know. It just feels wrong.
要是你能把三周来没时间拆封的
Would it feel wrong to use that robot gutter cleaner
清沟机拿出来用还会觉得不对吗
that's been sitting in the box for the last three weeks?
不会 那挺好的 好极了
No, that would feel right -- so right.
我告诉过你我称之为"一扫光"吗
Did I tell you I call it "The gutter done"?
你说过 我喜欢"一扫光"
You did! I love "Gutter done."
你太有幽默感了 太好玩了
It's your sense of humor. It's so fun.
好了 快别拍马屁了 你的目的达到了
Okay, stop drilling. You struck oil.
但前提是卢克也同意
But only if Luke's 100% cool with it.
当然了 我来搞定
Yeah, of course. I'm on it.
如果我们不去
You know, if we're not going,
就可以在床上多"玩"一会儿
we could stay in bed a little longer.
-不用了 谢谢 -好吧
- No, thank you. - Okay.
我不想15年后再重复上面的对话
Don't want to have this conversation again in 15 years.
你拿着那些样品干嘛
What are you doing with those swatches?
她随时都可能过来
She's gonna be here any minute.
我早就让你把这些婚礼用品收起来了
I told you to put all this wedding stuff away.
这两个真的是最好的颜色选择吗
Are these really our top-two choices for color palette?
为什么都是白色的
Why are they both white?
我朋友凯莎也这么问为什么你和大爸都是白人
That's what my friend Keisha asks about you and daddy.
与其把这些东西都藏起来
Instead of hiding all this stuff,
你何不直接告诉小帕我们要结婚了呢
why don't you just tell Pam we're getting married?
我会告诉她的 得等她做好心理准备
I will, when she's ready.
得在一个宽阔的场地上小心翼翼地告诉她
Carefully and preferably in a large, open field.
她是你姐姐 又不是绿巨人
She's your sister, not the Hulk.
我姐小帕情感异常脆弱
My big sister, Pam, is emotionally fragile
至今依然单身 所以她一旦发现
and she's still single, so when she finds out
我在她之前结婚...
I'm getting married before she is --
小心点
Look out.
她会比黄昏时的猫头鹰还要凶残
She can be meaner than a barn owl at sunset.
因为猫头鹰那时候起床吗
Because that's when they wake up?
没错 对猫头鹰来说那是早晨
Yep. That's morning time for a barn owl.
-她来了 -快点 藏起来
- It's her! - Quick! Hide!
没关系的 莉莉 过来
It's okay, Lily. Come on.
把她的蝴蝶结发箍拿下来
Oh, take that bow out of her hair.
我不想在我姐面前炫耀
I don't want to rub our daughter's adorableness
我们美丽可爱的女儿
in my barren sister's face.
-她来了 -你好啊 小帕
- There she is! - Hey, Pam!
该死的航班把我的行李箱弄丢了
Well, the damn airline lost my trunk.
-害我要做新衣服了 -真糟糕
- Now I'm gonna have to make new clothes. - Oh, no.
是啊
Yep.
我得找点东西捏捏
I need to squeeze something.
-过来 莉莉 -我就免了吧
- Get over here, Lily. - I'm good.
她有点害羞
Yeah, well, she's shy.
小帕 我们有个重大消息
So, Pam, we've got some big news.
说起重大消息
Speaking of big news --
你记得我以前照顾过的那个丑姑娘吗
You remember that little ugly girl i used to babysit,
名叫布兰妮·霍尔纳
Britney Horner?
-记得 -她去年夏天结婚了
- Yeah. - Well, she got married last summer,
现在怀上双胞胎了
and now she's pregnant with twins.
瞧瞧 丑女婚姻孩子双丰收 我一无所有
So, if you're keeping track, that's ugly -- 2, me -- nothing.
你们要说什么消息
What's your news?
就是...
Well...
我们要买一台新烘干机
We're getting a new dryer.
真为你们高兴
Well, I'm very happy for y'all.
谢谢
Thank you.
我怎么就从没买过新烘干机
How come I never get a new dryer?
妈 从你对外公有记忆起
Mom, in all the time you've known grandpa,
他曾经说过"流溢"这个词吗
has he ever used the word "Fluxions"?
我没听他说过这个"F"开头的词
That is not an f-word I have heard him use.
他在"和朋友比拼写"游戏中打败了我
He's beating me in "Words with friends."
这怎么可能
How is that even possible?
你不是应该跟你的朋友一起玩
Shouldn't you be playing "Words with friends"
"和朋友比拼写"吗
with friends?
外公就是我的朋友啊
Grandpa is my friend.
当然了 一点都不可悲 什么
Of course he is. That's not sad. What?
早上好 伙计 戴着枕头干什么
Morning, buddy. What's with the pillow?
为了足球啊
It's for soccer.
看比赛看得我脖子都酸了
My neck gets pretty tired watching all those games.
是哦
Right.
对啊 我猜也是
Yeah, I'll bet.
听着 你爸爸和我刚在讨论
Say, listen, your dad and I were just talking
今天你可能不想我们陪你去比赛了
about you maybe wanting to go to the game without us today.
不过这完全由你决定
But it's totally up to you.
你要怎样都行 因为我们非常爱你
Whatever you want because we love you very much.
对 你可以跟你的队友一起去
Right. You can either ride with some of your teammates,
像洛杉矶国王队一样
like the L.A. Kings,
你也可以跟我们一起去
or you can ride with us,
就像歌洛莉亚和你外公带着乔去玩
like how Gloria and grandpa take Joe to playdates.
专业运动员 还是小屁孩
Professional athlete, little poopy baby --
-你决定 -我跟麦克斯一起去
- Your call. - I'll get a ride with Max.
-很好 -你确定真的没问题吗
- Great! - Are you sure it's okay?
对啊 没事啊
Yeah, it's fine.
我能借一下你的眼罩吗
Hey, can I borrow your sleep mask?
-当然 -太好了
- You bet. - Awesome.
好耶 我太爱这孩子了
Yes! I love that kid.
如果我们只有这一个孩子
Can you imagine how easy it would be
生活该是多么轻松啊
if it was just him?
我是说...
I mean...
我知道你的意思
I know what you mean.
你觉得那样算叠好了吗
You call that folded?
军队级细致严谨的品格哪里去了
Where's that military precision?
我们海军不用叠连体衣
We didn't fold many onesies in the navy.
我回来了
I'm back!
医生怎么说
What did the doctor say?
他说我的眼睛没问题
He said my eyes are perfect.
他说这话时眼睛看着哪里呢
Where was he looking when he said it?
我确信歌洛莉亚需要配副眼镜
Pretty sure Gloria needs glasses.
过去几个月 她一直在挣扎
The last couple of months, she's been struggling.
我要这个 看起来很不错
I'll take this one. It looks very good.
那是他们的地址 老花眼
That's their address, Magoo.
他有测试你的视力吗
Did he even give you an eye test?
他先拿勺子盖住一只眼睛
He put the spoon in one eye,
然后又盖住另一只
the spoon in the other eye,
又拿眼药水滴了滴
The puff puff, the eye drops.
两眼都是完美的1.0 谁才是老花眼
20/20. Now who's the Magoo?
那是什么鸟语
What the hell language was that?
你看到她新做的指甲吗
Did you see that fresh coat of nail polish?
她根本没去看医生
She never went to the doctor.
她为什么要撒谎
Why would she lie?
她很自负 曼尼
She's vain, Manny.
她不想戴眼镜
She doesn't want to wear glasses.
那她只是在伤害她自己
Well, she's only hurting herself.
-想必你一定饿了 -饿死了
- Okay, I hope you're hungry. - Starving.
那架该死的航班没有烤牛肉了
That damn airline ran out of roast beef.
还试图说服我
Tried to fast talk me
吃什么"阴嘴豆泥"
into eating something called "Hoo-mus."
鹰嘴豆泥 其实非常美味
Oh, hummus -- it's actually really delicious.
你会喜欢...
You would like tha-- uh. Oh.
-这是什么 -是个玩偶
- What's this? - Oh, uh, that's an action figure.
是一对新郎
It's two grooms.
有天骄阳似火 两个玩偶
They melted together in the car
在车里融化在一起了
on a very, very hot day.
那天43度
It was 103.
我的爹地们要结婚了
My daddies are getting married.
你的两位爸爸要结婚了吗
Your dads are getting married?
这不科学啊
That can't be right.
我的朋友凯莎也这样说
That's what my friend Keisha says.
是真的吗
Is this true?
小帕 说实话 我们是打算告诉你的
Pam, honest to goodness, we were gonna tell you.
你快过来
Get over here, you!
她抱住我了
She's got me.
天啊
Well, damn!
这是我听过的最好的消息
This is the greatest news I've ever heard!
听你这样说我真高兴 小帕
Oh, I am so happy to hear you say that, Pam.
当然啦
Of course. Oh!
我想让我的小弟弟得到幸福
I want my baby brother to be happy.
既然在分享好消息 我也有一个
And as long as we're sharing, I have some news.
你记得博·约翰逊吗
You remember Bo Johnson?
天啊 我怎么会忘记
Oh, my gosh, how could I forget? Oh!
他是我的第一个暗恋对象
He was my first crush.
求你别告诉我他那张帅气的脸毁了
Please tell me nothing happened to his face.
他摔在什么东西上了
What did he fall into?
他和我摔入爱河了
He fell into me.
我们订婚了
We're engaged!
-你说什么 -博和我要结婚了
- Say what? - Bo and I are getting married!
太棒了 小卡 难道这不是好消息吗
That is fantastic! Cam, isn't this great news?
你快过来
Come here, you. Oh!
是啊 太棒了
Yeah. So great.
快来加入我 快
Get in on this! Come on!
谢谢你跳起来
Thank you for jumping.
我并不为错过卢克的足球比赛而内疚
I didn't feel guilty for missing Luke's soccer tournament
因为我有一大堆家务事
because I had a ton of errands
我觉得我得花一整天才能做完
I figured would take me all day to finish.
但不知为什么 事情办得相当顺利
But for some weird reason, I was flying through my list.
我每次都排到最短的队
I ended up in every short line.
路上也是一路绿灯
I made every green light.
这真是报应
It was the ultimate karmic bitch-slap.
因为我突然无事可做了
Because suddenly I had no more errands,
也就是说没有借口了
which meant no more excuses,
我必须得去无聊的足球比赛了
which meant me at that boring soccer tournament.
嗨 你来啦
Hi. There you are.
你儿子踢得棒极了
Your son is playing so great.
-不 我是卢克的妈妈 -我知道
- No, I'm Luke's mom. - No, I know.
-他今天表现得非常好 -卢克吗
- He's been amazing all day. - Luke?
卢克啊
Oh! Luke?
来一杯吗
Here, you want one?
不用 谢谢 我今天喝过咖啡了
Uh, no, thanks. I'm coffeed out.
-亲爱的 这是桑格利亚酒 -好吧
- Oh, honey, it's sangria. - Well, all right.
毋庸置疑了 外公在作弊
Okay, that's it. Grandpa's cheating.
对歌洛莉亚吗
On Gloria?
他怎么可能找到个更性感的
How could he possibly do better?
不 不是对歌洛莉亚 是这个游戏
No, not on Gloria -- on this game.
我从来没输给谁过
I've never lost it to anyone.
继续和外公玩单词游戏
Keep playing word games with grandpa,
你永远都别想了[失去贞操]
and you never will.
姑娘们
Hey, girls!
那东西是什么
Hey. What is that thing?
你是问它叫什么
What do they call it,
还是问它应该被叫做什么
or what should they have called it?
-不想知道了 -等等等等
- Never mind. - Uh, wait, wait, wait!
这是清沟机
It's a gutter cleaner.
女士们 我向你们展示未来
Ladies, I give you the future.
你们见过我多少次从梯子上摔下来啊
How many times have you girls seen me fall off this ladder?
现在摔倒的次数会少一些了
Now that's gonna happen less.
看来你的
Looks like your, uh,
清沟机卡在什么东西上了
gutter cleaner is stuck on something.
没关系
Not a problem.
这神器能检测出堵塞物 然后加大功率
This baby detects blockage and then ramps up the power.
所以我给它取了个外号 "一扫光"
That's why I've nicknamed it "The gutter done."
-爸爸 -停下
- Dad! - Stop!
抱歉 已经停不下来了
Sorry, it's such a missed opportunity.
天啊 天啊 天啊
Aah! Oh, my god, oh, my god, oh, my god!
-怎么 出什么事了 -这是个鸟巢
- What? What happened? - It's a bird's nest!
-不是吧 -小鸟都死了
- No! - And they're all dead!
-天啊 -你杀了它们
- Oh, my god! - You killed them!
宝贝 凶手不是我
Honey, it wasn't me!
而是机器人
It was the robot!
瞧瞧它
Look at it.
它还浑然不知
It doesn't know!
对不起
I'm sorry!
妈妈 妈妈 来帮忙
Mom! Mom! Help!
怎么了 出什么事了
What?! What happened?!
-我刚吃了一把老鼠药 -为什么
- I just ate a handful of this rat poison. - Why?!
我以为这是什锦干果仁
I thought it was trail mix.
我怎么把它们放在一起了
Why do I keep it so close together?
我去叫救护车
I'll call 911!
给 读出盒子上的内容
Here, read the box!
告诉我上面写着要怎么做
Tell me what it says to do!
快
Hurry!
-上面写着... -我没多少时间了
- It says... - I don't have much time!
里面...
In the...
-我就这样死了 -什么
- And I'm dead. - What?
你宁愿你老公被毒死
You'd rather kill your husband
也不愿承认你需要戴眼镜
than admit you need glasses.
-妈 你真狠心 -这不是毒药吗
- Wow, mom. - It's not poison?
的确有老鼠药
Oh, there's rat poison,
我也的确把它和什锦干果仁放得很近
and I do keep it dangerously close to the trail mix,
但这是为了指出
but this was to point out
你的虚荣可能是致命的
that your vanity could be fatal.
我就知道你们在骗我
I knew this was all a trick.
所以我才假装看不清盒子上的字
That's why I acted like I couldn't read that box!
有多少人会这么用心良苦假装死掉啊
How many people have to pretend to die, Gloria?
这简直不合情理
It just doesn't make any sense.
小帕和博·约翰逊
Pam and Bo Johnson?
-我的博·约翰逊 -什么叫"我的"
- My Bo Johnson? - "My"?
你为旧情人这么吃醋 我该为此烦恼吗
Should it bother me that you're this jealous of an old crush?
别说傻话了
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
博是直男
Bo is straight.
他可能永远不会爱上我
He'd probably never go for me.
天啊 是博打来的
Oh, my gosh, it is Bo!
瞧瞧 他比以前更帅了
Look, he's hotter than ever.
-我要接电话 -不行
- I'm gonna answer it. - No, you can't.
我可以 我们也算是一家人了
Yes, I can. We're practically family.
喂 哥们 我是小卡
Hey, dude. It's Cam.
小卡在哪呢
Where?
挺不错的 非常非常好
Been good -- been real, real good.
你和小帕在一起了啊
So, you and Pam, huh?
你最好对我老姐好一点
Hey, better be good to my old sis,
不然我就把你摔倒在地
or I'll have to wrestle you down.
-天啊 -问你个问题
- Oh, my God. - Hey, question --
我给你做的友谊手镯你还留着吗
Do you still have that friendship bracelet that I made for you?
好吧
Oh, okay.
好吧 你先忙 我让小帕给你回电话
Yeah, okay, if you're busy, I'll have Pam call you back.
博 恭喜你啊
Hey, and, Bo, congratulations.
你也是
You too.
-你能相信吗 -你又回归基佬啦
- Can you believe it? - Oh, and we're gay again.
这完全不合情理
It just doesn't make sense.
他肯定是对我们的钻井权有企图
I mean, he's got to be after our drilling rights.
我就知道
I knew it.
所以我才不想告诉你
This is why I didn't want to tell you.
我知道你没法承受你的梦中情人
I knew you couldn't stand the thought
被我搞定了的这个现实
of me landing the man of your dreams!
"梦中情人"这词太过了
"Dreams" is strong.
信不信由你 博和我真心相爱
Believe it or not, Bo and I are in love.
他觉得我很漂亮 他是对的
He thinks I'm beautiful, and he's right.
顺便说一句 博的土地是我们家的两倍大
And for the record, Bo has twice the land we do.
他对我的钻井权绝对没有半点兴趣
He has absolutely no interest in my drilling rights!
至少不是那种"钻"井权
Not that kind, at least.
好了 大家都淡定
Okay, let's just relax.
来吧 小帕 想再把我抱起来吗
Hey, hey, come on, Pam, do you want to pick me up again?
-他们警告过我 -谁警告过你
- They warned me, you know. - Who warned you?
全家人都说你会接受不了这个现实
The whole family said you wouldn't take it well.
自从你因为无法在农场存活
Ever since you moved to the city
而不得不搬到城里以后
'cause you couldn't hack it on the farm.
-"无法存活" -是的 没错
- "Couldn't hack it"? - Yeah, that's right.
大家都知道 小卡 你不是农场强人
Everyone knows, Cam, you're not farm strong.
收回你说的话 帕梅隆·杰西卡·塔克
You take that back, Pameron Jessica Tucker!
我才不呢 你是个软弱的娘炮
I will not! You are weak and weepy.
所以我们什么都不敢告诉你
That's why we can't ever say anything to you
因为我们知道你会反应过度闹个歇斯底里
'cause we know you'll crumble into a big heaping mess!
你说我才是那个需要别人小心对待
Oh, are you saying I'm the one people have to step around --
那个家里的爱哭鬼小帕吗
that I'm the Pam of the family?
你是说家里的爱哭鬼小卡吧
You mean the Cam of the family?!
因为大家都这么叫你
'cause that's what we all call it!
好了 够了
Okay, that's enough!
够了 够了
That's enough! That's enough!
你知道吗 我可是奶奶的最爱
You know what? Well, I was gammy's favorite!
-够了 -真的吗
- That's enough! - Really?
-当然 -拜托 够了
- Yeah! - Come on! Enough!
住嘴
No!
帕"梅隆" 你家人都叫这名儿吗
Seriously -- Pameron?
好球 卢克
Oh! Way to go, Luke!
-这孩子太棒了 -太棒了
- The kid's amazing. - Amazing.
-太厉害了 -是吧 喂
- So great. - Right? Hello?
-克莱尔 -菲尔
- Claire? - Phil?
亲爱的 我正想打给你呢
Oh, hi, honey, I was -- I was just about to call you.
我弄死了一窝小鸟
I killed a bunch of baby birds.
-什么 -我的机器人把鸟窝给端了
- What? - My robot wiped out the nest.
现在鸟妈妈正瞪着我呢
And now the mom's just staring at me.
它们能记住人的长相
They recognize faces, you know.
我在纪录片上看到过
I saw it in a documentary.
亲爱的 我相信那只是个意外而已
Sweetie, I'm sure it was just an accident.
要是我们去看卢克的比赛
None of this would have happened
就不会发生这种事情了
if we'd just gone to Luke's game.
-我们这父母做得太差劲了 -不会
- We're terrible parents for not going. - No. No.
那是哨声吗 你在哪里
Was that a whistle? Where are you?
我刚路过一个建筑工地
Um, I-I'm just walking by a construction site.
变态
Pervs!
对不起 对不起 没说你
Sorry. Sorry. Not you.
但愿卢克不会怪我们
I hope Luke's not mad at us.
不会 他没事的 亲爱的
No, he's fine, honey.
也可能有事 也可能会怪我们
Or he's not. He -- he could be mad.
我们不知道 我们猜不到
We don't know. We won't -- we won't know.
我马上就回去了
I'll -- I'll be home soon, though.
我爱你 好的 再见
I love you. Okay, bye-bye.
谢谢你 棒极了
Thank you. It was great.
卢克 卢克 卢克
Hey, Luke, Luke, Luke,
别告诉你爸我来过 你踢得真棒
Don't tell your dad I was here, all right? Great game.
克莱尔
Claire?
跟爸爸说晚安
Say good night to daddy.
晚安 好儿子
Mwah! Good night, my boy.
外公 你今天早上拼的那个词不错啊
Hey, grandpa, great word you played earlier today.
"朔望"到底是什么意思
What does "Syzygy" even mean?
意思是能得45分
It means 45 points. Ha!
大家好 你们还记得我姐小帕吧
Hey, everybody, you remember my sister, Pam.
小帕 你好
Oh, hi, Pam.
她来探望大家 顺便中伤你们几句
She's here to pay a visit and cast aspersions.
-别小孩子气了 -你才小孩子气
- Oh, grow up. - You grow up.
接得真好
Real good one.
大家好 我带了野猪肉
Hi, y'all. I brought boar.
我来帮你一起处理一下
Oh. Well, let me give you a hand with that.
小卡 听着 我知道你很生气
Cam, look, I know you're upset,
不过今晚就尽量别计较这个了
But please just try and let it go tonight.
她竟然说我才是那个脆弱敏感的人
Well, can you believe she said I'm the emotionally fragile one?
那简直是胡言乱语吧
I mean, how crazy is that?
-天啊 -"天啊"
- Boy. - "Boy"?
你是在露骨地表明
Is that your thinly veiled
你赞成她的说法吗
way of saying you agree with her?
你听着
Okay, you know what?
如果我很脆弱 我就会生气
If I was fragile, I would care,
可我没有 所以我不脆弱
but I'm not, so I don't.
-好的 -好的
- Good. - Good.
还有你知道吗 这衬衫太难看了
And you know what? That shirt washes you out,
要是有人把你当成黄皮蜡烛可别怪人家
so don't be shocked when someone mistakes you for a beige candle.
大家好
Hey, everyone.
-你好 卢克 -你好啊 伙计
- Hi, Luke. - Hey, buddy.
我很抱歉错过了你的比赛
I'm so sorry I missed your game.
我们都很抱歉错过了你的比赛
We are both so sorry we missed your game.
冥冥中我已经受到了惩罚
The universe punished me.
我对一群小乌鸦做了非常可怕的事情
I did something awful to a bunch of baby crows.
其实 那不叫"群鸦"
Actually, it's not a bunch of crows.
那该叫"群杀"
It's called a murder.
我知道我做了什么
I know what I did!
-比赛怎么样 -还行 没啥特别
- How was your game? - Fine. Nothing special.
你说"还行 没啥特别"是啥意思
What do you mean, "Fine, nothing special"?
好吧 其实16岁那组里有个妞
Well, there was this girl on the 16-year-old team
没穿胸罩
who wasn't wearing a bra.
所以还挺不错的
So that was cool.
可是乔什他妈给我发了短信
But Josh's mom texted me.
她说你踢得可好了
She said you were having a great game.
她喝多了
She drinks.
我马上就回来
I-I'll be right back.
-你好 菲尔 -你好 小帕
- Hey, Phil. - Hey, Pam.
不好意思
Oh. Sorry.
又是我爸妈
It's my parents again.
我快要结婚了
I'm getting married soon,
他们现在就呈现空"巢"老人的症状了
and they're already acting like they have empty nest syndrome.
我很感谢你
I appreciate you not saying
没跟你爸说我去看比赛的事
anything to your dad about me being there,
可你为何不告诉他你在赛场上的精彩表现
but why aren't you telling him what a great game you played?
我能看出来他错过比赛已经很难过了
I can tell he feels bad enough for missing it.
我不想让他感觉更糟
I don't want to make him feel worse.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
怎么了 出什么事了
Why? What's wrong?
我劝菲尔别去看卢克的比赛
I talked Phil into skipping Luke's game,
可是我去看了 他在赛场上发挥出色
and then I went, and, of course, he played the game of his life.
但现在卢克却不想
But Luke doesn't want to
跟菲尔谈那场比赛的事了
tell Phil about the game now
因为他不想伤害菲尔的感情
because he doesn't want to hurt his feelings.
我觉得卢克护着他爸的做法很有爱
Oh, well, I think it's sweet that Luke's protecting Phil.
在我们家 我们都得护着我姐姐
You know, we all have to protect my sister in my family
因为她敏感得可怕
because she's a disaster.
你能看得出来 对吧
I mean, you can see it, right?
我觉得她带猪肉来参加派对是挺奇葩的
I think it was a little weird she brought pig to a party.
只有我能说我姐姐
Hey! I can say it.
亲爱的
Hey, hon.
我为我之前的行为向你道歉
I'm sorry about what I did before.
我看到了这个 我觉得你戴上一定好看
I saw this, and I thought it would look beautiful on you.
你知道我就是不能生你的气
You know I can't stay mad at you
尤其是你给我买...
when you buy me...
眼镜 你这个混蛋
glasses, you son of a bitch!
戴上试试 你看起来还是会很迷人的
Just try 'em on. You'll still look gorgeous.
你买助听器那天我会戴上的
I will try them on when you buy hearing aids!
我的听力没什么问题啊
There's nothing wrong with my hearing.
我手机上有一款测试听力的应用
Um, I have a, uh, hearing-test app on my phone.
我们测测看
Let's do it!
-你来测 -好的
- You do it! - Okay.
60岁以下的人应该都能听到这个声音
Everybody under the age of 60 should be able to hear this.
-没错 听到了 -很清楚
- Yes. Heard that. - Yeah, definitely.
什么 你们撒谎 你们根本什么都没听着
What? You're lying. You didn't hear anything.
我们听见了 看到没 你聋了
We did! You see, you're deaf!
好的 70岁以下的
Okay, 70.
听见了
Mm-hmm. Yes.
这是什么 是她让你们这么做的吗
Oh, what is th-- did she put you up to this?
这样 外公 我放个声音大点儿的
Here, grandpa, I'll play you something even louder.
好的 这回我听见了
Okay, I heard that one.
我什么都没按
I didn't press anything.
看啊 谁作弊了啊
Oh, look who's a cheater.
不用担心 老大
Don't worry about it, big guy.
我闻不到柠檬的"酸味儿"
I have trouble smelling lemons.
我受够了
You know, I don't need any of this.
不过 我可以告诉你们我能听清楚什么
But I'll tell you what I can hear loud and clear.
那就是你们蹭饭时吧嗒嘴的声音
The sound of you all munching free food.
拜托 爸
Oh, come on, dad,
你是不是有点儿过于敏感了
aren't you being a little oversensitive?
这个问题可以请教我姐 小帕
Oh, well, we can consult my sister, Pam.
她自诩为"敏感学"专家
She's the self-appointed sensitivity expert.
-别计较了吧 -我就要计较
- Oh, let it go. - I will not let it go.
其实 我正想
In fact, I would like
让大家现在对我说实话
everyone to be honest with me, please, right now.
不用客气
No sugar-coating.
我姐姐似乎觉得你们大家
My sister here seems to think you all
-对我说话就得如履蛋壳 小心翼翼 -蛋壳
- have to walk on eggshells around me. - Eggshells.
你们是否觉得我很脆弱
Do you all think I'm so fragile
因为害怕我反应过度
you can't tell me things
而不敢告诉我一些事
for fear of how I will react?
-这个嘛 -克莱尔 打住 闭嘴
- Well. - Claire, don't. Zip. Bup-bup-bup.
不 请让她说
No, let her talk, please.
克莱尔 请发言
Claire, you have the floor.
好吧 你并不是不脆弱
W-well, you're not not fragile.
好吧 你不如举个例子
Okay, well, why don't you give me an example
说件因为担心我无法接受
of something you haven't told me
而没有告诉我的事
because you were worried I couldn't handle it?
说吧
Go on.
好的
All right.
上周我们本来约好吃午饭
Last week when we were supposed to have lunch
你取消了
and you canceled...
碧昂丝也在那餐厅
Beyonce was at the restaurant.
好吧 是歌手碧昂丝还是胡娇的狗
Okay. The singer or Pepper's dog?
歌手碧昂丝
The singer.
我离开餐厅时
And when I was leaving,
停在她身边打了个招呼
I-I-I stopped and I said hello to her
我们大概聊了十分钟
and we chatted for like 10 minutes.
好的 那真是太棒了
Okay, that's great.
我很高兴你有这样的经历
I'm glad you had that experience?
只是我不知道你跟她有什么好聊的
I mean, I don't know what you talked to her about,
因为她的歌你基本一无所知
seeing that you don't know any of her songs
除了《单身女人》
other than "Single ladies,"
那是众人皆知的口水歌
Which everyone knows.
-我爱那首歌 -我很意外你还听得到
- I love that song. － I'm surprised you can hear it.
真有意思 谁饿了
Well, this was fun. Who's hungry?
那只小公猪呢
Hey, where's that boar?
还有人要说吗
Okay, anyone else?
既然把话说开了
Well, since we're coming clean,
你太滥用"非凡"这个词了
you overuse the word "Divine."
只是一个冰淇淋三明治而已
It's just an ice-cream sandwich.
你却哭着喊着说"非凡"
You're the boy who cried "Divine."
好吧 以前我没注意到
Okay. Was not aware of that.
-知道了 -我有话说
- Duly noted. - Hey, I got one.
还记得圣诞节时你送我的蓝色盘式电话吗
Remember that blue rotary phone you gave me for Christmas?
-记得 -我扔了
- Yes. - I tossed it.
好的 可以问下原因吗
Okay. May I ask the reason?
让我觉得自己像
It made me feel like
《再见小鸟》里的安-玛格丽特
Ann-Margret in "Bye-bye Birdie."
-为何又要提到鸟 -还有人要说吗
- Why?! - Okay, anyone else?
我不喜欢
I don't really like the
-袖口这么夸张的衬衫 -不好意思
- shirts with the crazy cuffs. - Oh, I'm sorry.
你能把胸部压下去吗
Can you push your boobs down?
因为我听不到你说话
Because I couldn't hear you.
-又来了 -不 没有来
- Here we go. - No, no, here we don't go.
没事 我没事 好吗
This is fine. I'm fine, okay?
有时候你给我读睡前故事
Sometimes when you read to me,
我会假装睡着让你走
I pretend to fall asleep so you'll go.
我听到声音了
I heard that one.
你们的话我全听得一清二楚
Well, I heard you all loud and clear.
我得去洗手间
I have to use the restroom.
小卡 你很敏感又如何
So, Cam, you're sensitive.
有什么关系 这是你的优点之一
Big deal. It's one of your best qualities.
谢谢你 菲尔
Thank you, Phil,
很抱歉你那喜欢碧昂丝的老婆
and I'm sorry your Beyonce-loving wife
去看了卢克的比赛没带你
went to Luke's game without you.
看见没 农场强人
See? Farm strong!
你去看了卢克的比赛吗
You went to Luke's game?
我去了 菲尔 真是对不起
I did, Phil, and I am so sorry.
我本来没想去的
I did not mean to.
但他的表现太精彩了
But then he started playing the most amazing game,
然后我就舍不得走了
and I got so wrapped up in it.
我知道我应该打电话
I know I should have called.
对 你应该打电话
Yeah, you should've called.
你很厉害吗
You were amazing?
他太棒了 你要是去了就好了
Oh, he was incredible. I wish you'd been there.
那你为什么不让我去看
Then why'd you make me skip it?!
我就知道你有天赋
I knew you had it in you!
教练说他下周就能开球了
Oh, coach said he's gonna start next week.
你要开球吗 我太生你的气了
You're starting? I'm so mad at you!
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you!
-你还好吗 -很好
- Hey, how are you doing in here? - Fine.
我刚才发脾气 现在有些不好意思
I'm a little embarrassed about my outburst,
不过...
but otherwise...
你一下子要接受的东西太多了
You had a lot to take in.
作为律师 我应该早告诉你
As a lawyer, I should've told you,
永远不要问不想知道答案的问题
never ask questions you don't want the answer to.
我真的有那么糟吗
Am I really that much of a mess?
你没有听到我说的话吗
Are you not listening to me?
-有我站的地方吗 -不多
- Hey. Room in here for me? - Not really.
我为我说的话真心道歉
Look, I'm real sorry I said what I said.
不 你说得对
No, no, you're right.
我是"家里的爱哭鬼小卡"
I am the Cam of the family.
显然 我现在是"两个家里的小卡"
Apparently, I'm the Cam of two families, so...
你听到坏消息时
So what if you go a little cuckoo
会反应过度又怎么了
when you get bad news?
你听到好消息时也会反应过度
You also go all cuckoo when you hear good news.
这是我最喜欢你的一点
It's one of the things I love most about you.
不 这是真的
No, that's -- that's true.
我有好消息时 总是第一个
You're the -- you're the first person I call
打电话给你
when I have good news.
还记得我取下成人牙箍吗
I mean, remember when I got my adult braces removed?
你的牙齿看起来真是美得非凡
Your teeth look divi-- divine.
瞧 我也没办法 我就是天生乱激动
See? I can't help it. I'm a celebrator.
你当然是的
Of course you are.
我应该庆祝博那么幸运
And I should have celebrated how lucky Bo is
能找到你这么好的女人
to land a great gal like you.
瞧我 哭得跟小卡一样
Look at me. I'm crying like a Cam.
抱歉 不好的旧习惯
Sorry, old habits.
-我让你出丑你生气了吗 -别说了
- Are you mad because I embarrassed you? - Forget about it.
我也不会逼你戴眼镜了
And I'm gonna ease up on the glasses, too.
我只是担心
It's just that I worry, you know,
你什么也看不到
you're not seeing everything.
我老了 杰
I'm getting old, Jay.
曼尼小时候
When Manny was little,
我总是整天跟着他跑
I used to run around with him all day
一点也不累
without getting tired.
今天在乔的幼教班上
Today at Joe's baby class,
一个6岁的孩子得把我从球池里拉出来
a 6-year-old had to pull me out of the ball pit.
慢着 以前曼尼喜欢乱跑吗
Hold on. Manny used to run around?
所有的妈妈都那么年轻神气
All the mothers are so young and perky.
我讨厌做那里最老的一个
I hate being the oldest one there.
我恰恰喜欢你变老
Well, I for one love that you're getting older.
让我觉得和你更亲近了
It makes me feel closer to you.
就算我长皱纹皮肤松弛了你也会喜欢吗
So you'll like it if I get all wrinkly and saggy?
我可不会说非要那样才好
Well, I wouldn't make it a goal.
好吧 我戴眼镜
Okay, I'll wear them.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
你这里有皱纹
You have lines there.
我现在可以看得非常清楚
I can see them very clearly now with these --
阅读的时候戴就可以了
Okay, okay, these are just for reading.
我听不见她唠叨
I won't be able to hear her.
她看不见我的皱纹
She won't be able to see me.
我们会恩爱到永远
We'll be together forever.
恭喜啦
Congratulations.
你正式在"和朋友比拼写"中赢了我
You officially beat me in "Words with friends."
下次好运 孩子
Better luck next time, kid.
我一定得问下 你作弊了吗
Okay, I have to ask -- did you cheat?
你是这样才赢的吗
Is that how you won?
我从来不觉得你是个输不起的人
I never took you for a sore loser.
这不是答案
That's not an answer.
听着 以后你可能是这个家最聪明的人
Listen, one day you might be the smartest person in this family,
但那一天还没有到来
but today is not that day.
所以在你竭力污蔑我的词源学
So tread lightly before you assiduously malign
知识渊博的真实性前 三思而后说
the veracity of my etymological prowess.
杰·普里契特不玩了
Jay Pritchett out.
你把手机摔坏了 自以为是先生
You broke your phone, smarty-pants.
该死
Damn it!